Collection of Bookplates by J. Winfred Spenceley
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Bookplates by J. Winfred Spenceley
1894-1950
1895-1908
BKP 53
Yale University Arts Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
This collection contains over 200 ex-libris designs by J. Winfred Spenceley (1865-1908), an artist and engraver active during the so-called "golden age" of American bookplate design.
Andreini, Joseph Manuel, 1850-1932
Andrews, Irene Dwen, 1892-
Lowenhaupt, Warren Hiram, 1891-1967
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
J. Winfred Spenceley (1865-1908) was born in Boston, MA, and died in Chocorua, NH. He was trained in lettering and ornamental design for steel and copper plate engraving and worked as a bank note engraver and commercial illustrator. He moved from Boston to Chicago and even to Mexico City, before returning to Boston and focusing on bookplates. Spenceley produced over 200 ex-libris designs in addition to a variety of other commercial and fine art engravings.
Reference: Joseph Manuel Andreini, J. Winfred Spenceley: His Etchings and Engravings in the Form of Bookplates (New York: Privately Printed, 1910), 11.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains over 200 ex-libris designs by J. Winfred Spenceley (1865-1908), an artist and engraver active during the so-called "golden age" of American bookplate design. In addition to ex-libris, the collection includes signed artist's proofs, trial proofs, restrikes, and original sketches for both bookplates as well as other works. The collection also includes correspondence and printed ephemera – both by and about Spenceley – from a variety of sources.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Bookplates – Numbered. II. Bookplates – Unnumbered. III. Bookplates – Unidentified. IV. Other Works. V. Correspondence and Ephemera.
Bookplates, American; Bookplates; Spenceley, J. Winfred (Joseph Winfred), 1865-1908
- Bookplates – Numbered, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged numerically by checklist number – roughly chronological in order. Any correspondence or ephemeral materials relating to a specific bookplate are filed together with the bookplate.
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes bookplates #1-#217 by Spenceley, which are identified and numbered according to the descriptive checklist published by Andreini in 1910. Patrons for whom Spenceley created multiple bookplates are indicated with Roman numerals, according to the convention employed by Andreini.
  - #1 Oliver Wendell Holmes, 1895; 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #2 H. C. M. Thomson, 1895; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #3 Mary H. Fee, 1895; 12 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #4 Ralph Oliver Smith, 1895; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #5 Frederick Denison Lyon, 1895; 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #6 M. M. Sands, 1895; 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #7 1895 Alice Root Atkinson, 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #8 William M. Derby, Jr., 1895; 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #9 Tracy C. Drake, 1895; 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #10 J. Winfred Spenceley (I), 1896; 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes a description, or blazon, of the coat of arms.
  - #11 Noble Foster Hoggson (I), 1896; 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #12 Norman W. Harris, 1896; 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - #13 Boston Public Library, 1896; 6 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - #14 Charles Fry, 1896; 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - #15 Frederick Henry Prince, 1896; 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - #16 Dubois Henry Loux, 1896; 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - #17 Noble Foster Haggson (II), 1896; 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - #17 J. Winfred Spenceley (II), 1897; 16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Includes notes from Spenceley biography published in the Ex Libris Journal, vol. VIII.
  - #19 David W. Cheever, M. D., 1897; 4 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - #20 William Carver Williams, M. D., 1897; 10 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - #21 George Foster Barnes, 1897; 8 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - #22 Walter Conway Prescott (I), 1897; 19 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Includes two letters from Prescott. Also, one of the seals depicted is Harvard's.
  - #23 Hotel Touraine, Boston, 1897; 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #24 Henry Sargent Codman and Philip Codman, 1897; 5 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Includes the Boston Public Library memorial bookplate for Henry Sargent Codman.
  - #25a Henry Sturgis Grew, 1897; 5 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #25b Randolf Clark Grew, 1897; 4 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - #26 John Edward Devlin, 1897; 8 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #27 Fred H. C. Woolley, 1897; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - #28 Charles E. Cameron (I), 1897; 6 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #29 Charles E. Cameron (II), 1897; 16 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - #30 Minnie C. Holbrook, 1897; 13 items (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - #31 E. N. Hewins, 1897; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - #32 Andrew Smith, 1897; 15 items (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - #33 [Abram Garfield], 1897; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - #34 Margaret Van Zandt, 1897; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #35 Billerica Historical Society, 1897; 6 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - #36 William Archer Butterfield, 1897; 22 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - #37 Boston Browning Society, 1897; 5 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Includes an etching by F. T. Merrill for which Spenceley executed the lettering.
  - #38 Adele Tylden Low, 1897; 9 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - #39 Alphonso T. Clearwater, 1897; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - #40 20th Regiment, MVI, 1897; 5 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Includes a letter, dated 1949, from Frank S. Hatch to Irene D. Andrews Pace, regarding the exchange of Spenceley bookplates.
  - #41 James Rudolf Garfield, 1897; 4 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Includes part of a letter, dated 1939, from James R. Garfield.
  - #42 William C. Watt, 1898; 8 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - #43 Walter Conway Prescott (II), 1898; 15 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Includes a note describing the location of the landscape depicted in the bookplate.
  - #44 Frank W. Hastings, Jr., 1898; 5 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - #45 Teacher's College - Bryson Library, 1898; 4 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Includes a note stating that the artist is Charles R. Lamb, and the etcher is Spenceley.
  - #46 [Albert C. Bates], 1898; 4 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Includes a letter, dated 1948, from Albert C. Bates to Frank S. Hatch, indicating that Bates never accepted Spenceley's design. See also Folder 48.
  - #47 Edmund Jolliffe, 1898; 6 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    See also Folder 47.
  - #48 Levi W. Eaton, 1898; 8 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - #49 Marianne Beers Sterling Memorial, 1898; 3 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - #50 Bessie H. Williams, 1898; 6 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - #51 Henry A. Smith, 1898; 3 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - #52 Edward S. Stickney, 1898; 4 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Includes a note by Spenceley stating that E. D. French completed about half of this etching and then requested Spenceley's help to finish it, excepting the Hermes bust featured in the lower left of the design. This folder contains a proof of the plate as Spenceley left it as well as a finished print by French.
  - #53 Mathilde E. Thebaud, 1898; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - #54 Robert Scoville - Herbert Scoville, 1899; 6 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - #55 Eva Lewis, 1899; 13 items (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - #56 Charles Edmund Peck and Anna Bristol Peck, 1899; 6 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - #57 Charles Pfaff, 1899; 4 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - #58 Adrienne Adams Wickham, 1899; 9 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - #59 Gardiner Greene Hammond and Esther Lathrop Hammond, 1899; 7 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - #60 J. B. W., 1899; 6 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Folder contains the bookplate of Julia Bradford White.
  - #61 Women's Club of Wisconsin (I), 1899; 9 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - #62 Frances Sanford, 1899; 11 items (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - #63 Lois Kellogg, 1899; 4 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - #64 Detroit Public Library, 1899; 7 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    Includes a note explaining that there are two states, only one of which is in use.
  - #65 Charles Goddard Weld, 1899; 9 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - #66 George S. Chambliss, 1899; 4 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - #67 University of Missouri, 1899; 32 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - #68 Grace Anderson Smith, 1899; 9 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - #69 George Higginson, Jr., 1899; 7 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - #70 The W. H. Perry Library, 1899; 12 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #71 C. Will Chappell, 1900; 4 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - #72 Mary M. Emery, 1900; 6 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - #73 William Whiting, 1900; 6 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - #74 Maude Heyward, 1900; 5 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - #75 Allene Le C. Merrill, 1900; 5 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - #76 Henry Kidder Gilbert, 1900; 2 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - #77 Minerva Cushing Crocker, 1901; 4 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - #78 Elizabeth Hitchcock Brayton, 1901; 7 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - #79 Jennie Prince Black, 1901; 8 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - #80 Charles J. Livingwood, 1901; 3 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Includes a note describing in detail the Paris scene depicted in the bookplate.
  - #81 The Alton Road, 1901; 4 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - #82 Alice A. Dodsworth, 1902; 4 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - #83 Ethelbert Ide Low, 1901; 2 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - #84 Hannah Adams Pfaff, 1901; 5 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - #85 Zella Allen Dixon (I), 1901; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 86)
    Includes a letter, dated 1908, from Ms. Dixon to Mr. J. M. Andreini.
  - #86 Ohio State University (I) Outhwaite, 1901; 7 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    Includes an original drawing for this bookplate design.
  - #87 Dartmouth College Library (I), 1901; 10 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    Includes a note explaining that the bookplate features the names of 13 famous libraries and of five bibliographers.
  - #88 Henry Ladd Corbett, 1902; 11 items (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - #89 Mary Florence Taft, 1902; 5 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - #90 Fred Erwin Whiting, 1902; 7 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - #91a John Hays Gardiner, 1902; 8 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Includes a note with a description, or blazon, of the coat of arms.
  - #91b Robert Hallowell Gardiner, 1902; 5 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - #91c John Tudor Gardiner, 1902; 7 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - #92 John Wingate Weeks, 1902; 4 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Includes a note with a description, or blazon, of the coat of arms as well as a brief biography of Weeks.
  - #93 Redmond Conygham Stewart, 1902; 5 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - #94 Winfred Porter Truesdell, 1902; 9 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #95 Margaret F. G. Whitney, 1902; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - #96a, b, & c Berthe L. Welch, Berthe C. Welch (B. d'Alte Welch), A. Welch, 1902; 10 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    Includes a letter, dated 1950, from Frank S. Hatch to Irene D. Andrews Pace.
  - #97 Matthew Henry Taylor, 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - #98 Marie Winthrop, 1902; 12 items (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - #99 George H. Mifflin, 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - #100 Arthur Franklin Johnson, 1902; 7 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - #101 A. M. S., 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    General note
    Bookplate of Adelaide M. Smith.
  - #102 Hale Memorial, 1902; 16 items (Box 3, Folder 105)
    Bookplate commemorating "A Gift to the City of Keene, New Hampshire, in memory of George Silsbee Hale, by his sons Robert Sever Hale and Richard Walden Hale."
  - #103 Maud Teahon, 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - #104 Lowell M. Palmer (I), 1902; 11 items (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - #105 Veryl Preston, 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - #106 Ethel Randolph Thayer, 1902; 4 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - #107 University Club of Chicago, 1902; 5 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - #108 Horace Sweeney Oakey, 1902; 4 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - #109 Lowell M. Palmer (II), 1902; 6 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    Includes a note stating that Palmer was a famous collector of rare ferns and evergreens and that his home is named "Fernwood."
  - #110 George Clifford Thomas, 1902; 6 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - #111 Thos. N. Miller, 1902; 3 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - #112 Charles Rathbone Ballou, 1902; 3 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - #113 The Zeta Psi Club, 1902; 14 items (Box 4, Folder 116)
    Includes a note explaining that the design was based on an 18th-century plate by Fiquet.
  - #114 Julia Marion Hoyt, 1903; 2 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - #115 Lowell M. Palmer (III), 1903; 4 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - #116 Haven, 1903; 4 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    Bookplate of G. G. Haven, Jr. and E. I. Haven.
  - #117 Philander Chase Knox, 1903; 5 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - #118 Herbert Spencer Allen, 1903; 11 items (Box 4, Folder 121)
    Includes a note stating that the bookplate was designed by Frederick Garrison Hall and engraved by Spenceley.
  - #119 W. B. L., 1903; 3 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    Bookplate of W. B. Leeds.
  - #120 Henry Rogers Winthrop, 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - #121 Morris & Lenore Black, 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - #122 Lucy While Williams, 1903; 5 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - #123 Ohio State University (White Library), 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - #124 Georgia Medora Lee, 1903; 19 items (Box 4, Folder 127)
    Includes bookplate of Nathalie Collins, engraved by Shreve & Co., which is an exact copy of Spenceley's design for Lee.
  - #124 Mabelle Hattie Lee, 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - #125 Henry and Alice Young, 1903; 3 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - #126 Gifford Alexander Cochran, 1903; 4 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - #127 Robert Gorham Fuller, 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - #128 Helen Vernera Drake, 1903; 6 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - #129 Andrew Christian Zabriskie, 1904; 3 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - #130 Charles Stewart Smith, 1904; 4 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - #131 Martha Houghtaling Ingalls, 1904; 3 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - #132 Frederick Norton Finney, 1904; 5 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - #133 James Cowan Greenway, 1904; 6 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - #134 Harvard College Library, Nickerson Memorial, 1904; 7 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - #135 Harvard College Library - Von Maurer, 1904; 9 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - #136 M. K. G., 1904; 7 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    Bookplate of M. K. Gage.
  - #137 Sunday School, First Presbyterian Church, Chicago, 1904; 6 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    Includes a poem in 3 stanzas, "In Memoriam J. W. S.," by E. C., undated.
  - #138 Samuel Strong Spaulding, 1904; 5 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - #139 Roxana Atwater Wentworth Bowen, 1904; 3 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - #140 Ezra J. Warner, 1904; 3 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - #141 Arthur Curtiss James, 1904; 6 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Includes an obituary of James, dated June 1941, and a version of this bookplate entitled, "Wanderings of Aloha" – Aloha being the name of James's yacht.
  - #142 William Pierson Medical Library Association, 1904; 5 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - #143 Robert Sever Hale, 1904; 2 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - #144 Henrietta Eleanor Robinson, 1904; 3 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - #145 Library of the University of Michigan, 1904; 25 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - #146 Charles W. Chase, 1904; 5 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - #147 Charles Edward Holbrook, 1905; 8 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    Two of the bookplates are mounted on an advertisement from Dodd, Mead and Company, Stationery Department. In addition to Spenceley's design, the pamphlet also includes a reproduction of one of the earliest known bookplates, that of Hildebrand Brandenburg (circa 1470-1480).
  - #148 E. L. W. - W. M. S.[mith], 1905; 4 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - #149 George Lauder, 1905; 2 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - #150 Robert Stanton Brewster, 1905; 4 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - #151 University of California, 1905; 8 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - #152 George Lauder, Jr., 1905; 4 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - #153 George Herbert Palmer, 1905; 6 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - #154 Susan E. P. Forbes, 1905; 9 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    Bookplate of Susan E. Parsons Forbes.
  - #155 Eben MacBurney Byers, 1905; 3 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - #156 Mary Nixon Smith, 1905; 7 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - #157 Melchor Ocampo Manzo, 1905; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - #158 William F. Herrin, 1905; 6 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - #159 Zella Allen Dixon (II), 1905; 7 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - #160 Linda Thomas, 1905; 9 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - #161 H. O. Havemeyer, Jr., 1905; 12 items (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - #162 Georgia Medora Lee & Georgia Medora Preston, 1905 1908; 16 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - #163 Graycroft, 1905; 9 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - #164 Francis Gregory Wood, 1905; 3 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - #165 Gordon Abbott, 1905; 8 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - #166a Henry Lloyd, 3rd, 1905; 1 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - #166b Maria Lloyd King, 1905; 3 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - #167 Julia Folger Corson, 1905; 3 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - #168 Charles Henry Deere and Mary Little Dickinson Deere, 1905; 2 (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - #169 Helen Clay Frick, 1905; 5 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - #170 Childs Frick, 1905; 3 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - #171 George S. Goodrich, 1906; 8 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - #172 Frederick Starr, 1905; 9 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    Includes a note explaining the various Mexican and Central American subjects depicted in this bookplate.
  - #173 Atherton Clark, 1907; 8 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - #174 Josephine Elizabeth Izard, 1906; 5 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - #175 Women's Club of Wisconsin, 1906; 2 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - #176 Jane Sherrill Knowles, 1906; 13 items (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - #177 Philip Mesier Lypig, 1906; 6 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - #178 Harvard University Department of Agriculture, 1906; 9 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - #179 Henry Hollister Pease, 1906; 6 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - #180 Edward Stephen Harkness, 1906; 5 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - #181 Isaac N. Seligman, 1906; 8 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - #182 James Hobart Moore, 1906; 4 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - #183 Eleanor Whitney Watson & #184 Margery Willard Watson, 1906; 12 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - #185 Mabel Eleanor Dick, 1906; 3 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - #186 Charles Stewart Davidson, 1906; 4 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - #187 Alice R. Studebaker, 1907; 4 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - #188 Nathaniel Henry Burt, 1906; 5 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - #189 Charles Harvey Bentley, 1906; 8 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - #190 Adrian Hoffman Joline, 1907; 8 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - #191 Rochester Public Library, 1906; 6 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - #192 Joseph Husband, Esqre., 1907; 7 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - #193 T. Henry Foster, 1907; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - #194 Davenport Academy of Sciences, 1907; 6 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - #195 Library of the New Theatre, 1907; 23 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - #196 Dartmouth College Library (II), 1907; 17 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    Bookplate was designed by M. D. Bisbee and engraved by Spenceley.
  - #197 Jacob Chester Chamberlain, 1907; 6 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - #198 Helen Pierce Metcalf, 1907; 7 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - #199 Dorothy Furman, 1907; 9 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - #200 Joseph Manuel Andreini, 1907; 9 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    Includes a note stating that the plate was unfinished at the time of Spenceley's death and was retouched, vignetted, lettered, and refinished by Sidney L. Smith, after designs by Andreini.
  - #201 William Jay, 1907; 4 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - #202 Porcellian Library, 1907; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - #203 Mary E. Downey, 1907; 5 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - #204 Washington County Free Library, Hagerstown, MD, 1907; 7 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - #205 Charles Phelps, 1907; 4 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - #206 Mitchell Public Library, 1908; 5 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - #207 Charles Pelham Curtis, 1908; 5 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - #208 Ellen Judith Crane, 1908; 2 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - #209 The Reading Club, St. Matthew's School, 1908; 9 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - #210 Kenneth Minius Andreini, 1909; 9 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - #211 Richard Colby Spenceley, 1904; 8 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - #212 Clare Holbrook Spenceley, 1907; 11 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - #213 J. M. A., 1908; 9 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    Bookplate of J. M. Andreini. Includes a note stating that the plate was unfinished at the time of Spenceley's death and was retouched, vignetted, lettered, and refinished by Sidney L. Smith, after designs by Andreini.
  - #214 Wisteria Cottage Press - Zella Allen Dixon, 1903; 3 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - #215 Fruitledge [Henry Rogers Winthrop], 1906; 4 (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - #216 George Foster Barnes, 1897; 2 (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - #217 Bishop's House, Quincy, Illinois, 1907; 4 (Box 6, Folder 221)
- Bookplates – Unnumbered, Series II
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the patron.
  This series includes unnumbered bookplates which were identified in Andreini's checklist either as "not in use as book plates" or as "unfinished coppers."
  - Archbishop's House, Boston, 1909; 3 (Box 6, Folder 222)
    Bookplate features the coat of arms of Archbishop O'Connell.
  - Bowdoin College Library, 1908 1915; 12 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    Includes a note stating that the plate was unfinished at the time of Spenceley's death and later completed by A. N. Macdonald.
  - Boston Public Library, undated; 22 items (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Chicago and Southern States Association, 1895; 1 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Frank Wilkinson Darling and Mary Gorton Darling, 1908; 11 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    Includes a note stating that this was an unfinished plate.
  - Great Neck Library, 1909; 1 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    Includes a note stating that the unfinished plate was in possession of Mrs. Spenceley and was printed in 1909.
  - The Lord Fund, 1908; 2 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    Includes a reproduction of Spenceley's original drawing for this bookplate, of which only the seal of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York was engraved.
  - [Franklin Butler] Lord Memorial, 1908; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 229)
    Includes a reproduction of Spenceley's reduced design, which was never completed.
  - Maria Gerard Messenger, 1909; 2 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    Includes two trial proofs which were pulled in 1909.
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants in Massachusetts, 1897 1909; 9 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    Includes a trial proof pulled in 1909.
  - [Spenceley] Memorial Plate, 1906-1909; 6 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    This J. W. S. design was started by Spenceley and completed by Sidney L. Smith as a memorial bookplate.
- Bookplates – Unidentified, Series III
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the patron with a group of unidentified materials at the end.
  This series includes bookplates that have been attributed to Spenceley by various bookplate collectors, although none of the materials are identified in Andreini's checklist. The series also contains some trial proof plates as well as a bookplate designed for Spenceley by Herbert Gregson in 1902.
  - "Unidentified, Oddments, Exotica, etc.", 1899-1903; 32 (Box 6, Folder 233)
    Contains plates for the following: Bell, Bishop's House (Springfield, MA), Anne M. H. Brewster, Traver Briscoe, Charles Scribner's Sons Stationery Department, Harvard College Library, John Gerard Heckscher, Arthur Curtiss James, Georgia Medora Lee, George Barr McCutcheon, Norman Williams Public Library, Walter Conway Prescott, Spenceley, Suffolk Club, Albert May Todd, University Club, Samuel Wilde, Sarah Gilbert Wood, unidentified.
- Other Works, Series IV
  Arranged by type of illustration.
  This series includes examples of other engravings and etchings by Spenceley, most of which are not directly related to bookplates.
  - Various Commercial Plates, 1894-1908 undated; 31 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    Includes a variety of plates and trial proofs by Spenceley, most of which are commercial illustrations.
  - Prints Marked "Estelle", 1909 undated; 8 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    Includes a series of landscape prints, all annotated with the name "Estelle." Spenceley created nature studies to illustrate a book by Marcus Blakey Allmond (1851-1909), called Estelle: An Idyl of Old Virginia, and Other Poems.
  - Numbered Landscape Prints, 1909 undated; 20 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    Includes various states of landscape prints, belonging to a numbered series.
  - Various Landscape Prints, 1908 undated; 15 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    Includes plates and trial proofs of various landscapes prints.
  - Various Decorative & Commercial Decorative, undated; 36 (Box 6, Folder 238)